bellevuecollege.edu 2013-12-27

# Bellevue College Website Privacy Notice

Thank you for visiting the Bellevue College (BC) website and reviewing our Privacy Notice. This statement addresses collection, use and security of and access to information that may be obtained through use of Bellevue College’s website.  This notice covers the following topics:

## Information Collected and How It’s Used

### Information We Collect if You Only Browse this Site

If you do nothing during your visit to our website other than browse, read pages, or download or print information, Bellevue College gathers and stores certain information about your visit. The information gathered does not identify you personally. We automatically collect and store the following information when browsing the site:

  * The Internet Protocol (IP) Address and domain name used. The IP Address is a numerical identifier assigned either to your Internet service provider or directly to your computer.  IP addresses are used to direct Internet information between computing systems.   This address can be translated to determine the domain name of your service provider (e.g. xcompany.com or yourschool.edu);
  * The type of browser, operating system and screen resolution used on your computer; 
  * The date and time you visited this site; 
  * The web pages or services you accessed at this site; and 
  * The website you visited prior to coming to this website (referring sites or links).

The information automatically collected or temporarily stored by the college is used anonymously to monitor bandwidth use (performance) of servers and website traffic trends and patterns.  The college analyzes this information to determine how visitors are using our web-based content and services so we may continually improve the site's usefulness to the public.

### Information We Collect if You Volunteer Information

If during your visit to our website you participate in a survey, send an e-mail, or perform some other transaction on-line, the following additional information will be collected:

  * The e-mail address and contents of an e-mail if sent to anyone with a Bellevue College e-mail address; 
  * Any information you volunteer in response to a survey;
  * Any information you volunteer through an online form for any other purpose.

  The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats you send us.

We use your e-mail address to respond appropriately.  This may be to respond to you, to address issues you may identify, to further improve our website, or to forward the e-mail to another agency for appropriate action. Survey information is used for improving the college systems or any outside services that the college offers. Information from other online forms is used to enable college processes and services. 

## Personal Information and Choice

“Personal information” is defined as information about a person that is readily identifiable to that specific individual.  Personal information may include an individual's name, address, and phone number.  A domain name or IP address is not considered personal information. 

The college does not collect personal information about you unless you voluntarily provide it to us by sending us e-mail, participating in a survey, or completing an online form.  You may choose not to contact us by e-mail, participate in a survey or to provide any personal information using an online form. Your choice to not participate in these activities will not impair your ability to browse Bellevue College’s website and read or download any information provided on the site. 

If personal information is requested on the website or volunteered by the user, state law and the federal Privacy Act of 1974 may protect it.  However, this information is a public record once you provide it, and may be subject to public inspection and copying if not protected by federal or state law.

If you believe that your personal information is being used for a purpose other than what was intended when submitted, you may contact the Public Records Officer [link] as shown in the Contact Information Section of this statement.

Bellevue College is a general audience site and we do not knowingly collect any personal information from children.  Users are cautioned that the collection of personal information requested from or volunteered by children online or by e-mail will be treated the same as information given by an adult, and may be subject to public access.

## Public Access to Information

In the State of Washington, laws exist to ensure that government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by state government.  At the same time, there are exceptions to the public's right to access public records that serve various needs including the privacy of individuals.  Exceptions are provided by both state and federal laws. 

All of the information collected at this site becomes public records that may be subject to inspection and copying by members of the public, unless an exemption in law exists. [RCW 42.56.070](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/RCW/default.aspx?cite=42.56.070) [Links to: http://apps.leg.wa.gov/RCW/default.aspx?cite=42.56.070] states that:

Each agency, in accordance with published rules, shall make available for public inspection and copying all public records, unless the record falls within the specific exemptions of the Public Records Act or other statute which exempts or prohibits disclosure of specific information or records. To the extent required to prevent an unreasonable invasion of personal privacy interests protected by [RCW 42.56.210](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/RCW/default.aspx?cite=42.56.210) and [42.56.320](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/RCW/default.aspx?cite=42.56.320), an agency shall delete identifying details in a manner consistent with RCW 42.56.210 and RCW 42.56.320 when it makes available or publishes any public record; however, in each case, the justification for the deletion shall be explained fully in writing.

In the event of a conflict between this Privacy Notice and the Public Records Act or other law governing the agency’s disclosure of records, the Public Records Act or other applicable law will control.

The complete Revised Code of Washington (RCW) is available at: <http://apps.leg.wa.gov/RCW/>

## Nondisclosure of Certain Personal Information

The following laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing the personal information about you except for directory information. Only directory information can be released without student's authorization. Students must sign a release in order to have any other information disclosed or to withhold all information. Education information may be released to other institutions that have requested the records and in which the student seeks or intends to enroll. Information may be released to a third party without student's consent if an emergency situation exists or if information is requested officially by means of a subpoena, court order or legal report. Additionally, Congress requires student information to be released to military recruiters if officially requested. Directory information may include student's name, address, telephone number, date and place of birth, major fields of study, participation in officially recognized activities and sports, weight and height of members of athletic teams, dates of attendance, degrees and awards received, the most recent previous educational agency or institution attended by the student, and other similar information.

Section 438, Public Law 90-247 Title IV, as amended, 88 Stat 571-574 (20 USC 1232g) otherwise known as the Buckley Amendment Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act.   

  * [RCW 42.17.310](http://search.leg.wa.gov/pub/textsearch/ViewRoot.asp?Action=Html&Item=15&X=815105327&p=1) (a) and (ss) exempts the following from public inspection and copying: (a) Personal information in any files maintained for students in public schools, patients or clients of public institutions or public health agencies, or welfare recipients; (ss) Credit card numbers, debit card numbers, electronic check numbers, card expiration dates, or bank or other financial account numbers supplied to an agency for the purpose of electronic transfer of funds, except when disclosure is expressly required by law. 

You may be required to provide certain personal information when you use the Web-enabled applications that are described below.

### Admissions Application Online

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to apply online to the college. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to provide you with this service over the Web, and you will have to apply in person or via the mail with paper application form. 

The online version of the admissions application requires you provide your full name, e-mail address, username, password, birth date, and program of study. You may also choose to provide optional details such as purpose of attending. You may update any of this information at any time by logging in to your personal profile (account).

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Requesting Information via the Website 

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information when inquiring about program, admissions, or college information when requesting this using the “Get Started” website. You may choose not to provide this information and alternatively phone the college directly at 425 564-2222 for information or come to the Student Service Center in person.  

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Requesting Personalized Information via the Website

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information when signing up to receive personalized information using the “Get Started” website.  You may choose not to provide this information, but we will be unable to provide you this service. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### View/Verify Records Block

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view blocks on your record via the Web. Providing this personal information is required in order for the college to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, however if you do not, we are unable to provide this service via the web. Alternatively, you may request this information in person or by phone.  

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Credit Card Payments

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to make credit card payments over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity and to verify your credit card number and expiration date. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to apply tuition and fee payment over the web and you will have to make credit card payments in person, by phone or by mail. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Degree Audit

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to perform a degree audit of your records using the online degree audit website application.  Personal information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display a degree audit of your records over the web, and you will have to request a degree audit in person.  

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Donations

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to donate money over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity and to verify your credit card number and expiration date. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to donate over the web.  Alternatively, you can donate in person, over the phone or by mail. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Retrieving Tax Information / Hope and Lifetime Learning Tax Credit

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to allow you to view and copy course enrollment and payment information. The information is required in order to provide you with the tax information needed for compliance with the Internal Revenue Service reporting requirements for the Hope and Lifetime Leaning tax credits. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it, we will be unable to display your enrollment and payment information and you will have to obtain a copy of your enrollment and payment records either in person or by mail.

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Registration

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to register for classes over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it you will be unable to register for classes over the web, and you will have to register for classes in person. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Registration Appointment

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain your registration appointment information over the Web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your registration appointment information over the Web, and you will have to obtain your registration appointment in person. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Schedule Planner

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to check requisites while using schedule planner. The information is required in order to access your academic and testing records. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to verify your eligibility for enrollment into certain classes and you may be blocked from enrolling into those classes. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Student Address Change

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to change your address over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to change your address over the Web, and you will have to change your address in person. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Student PIN Change

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to change your personal identification number over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to change your PIN over the Web, and you will have to change your PIN in person. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Student Schedule

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your quarterly schedule. The information is required in order to verify you identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your quarterly schedule over the Web, and you will have to obtain a copy of your quarterly schedule in person. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Unofficial Transcript

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to view your unofficial transcript over the Web. This information is required in order for the college to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to display your unofficial transcript over the Web, and you will have to view your unofficial transcript in person or receive it through the mail. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information. 

### Student ID (SID) Number Lookup

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to lookup your Student ID Number over the web. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it you will be unable to lookup your Student ID Number over the web and you will have to request it in person.

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information. 

### Student Account Management (SAM) Tool

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain and manage your student network account over the web.  The information is required in order to verify your identity as a student of the college. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it we will be unable to create your student network account and you will have to obtain and manage your student network account in person. 

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to obtain and manage your student network account over the web.  The information is required in order to verify your identity as a student of the college. You may choose not to provide this information via the web page. If this is your choice, you may alternatively request assistance in obtaining and managing your student network account in person at the Open Computer Lab in N250.  Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you.

Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Student Technology Support Center 

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information via the web in order to request assistance with campus technology. The information is required in order to verify your identity and status as a current student. You may choose not to provide this information via the web, but if you choose not to use this resource, you will be required to seek assistance in person at the Open Computer Lab in N250. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Blackboard Vista

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to take online classes that use Blackboard Vista. The information is required in order to verify your identity. You may choose not to provide this information, but if you choose not to provide it you we will be unable to verify your identity over the web and you will be unable to take online classes. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### MyBC

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information to create an account to gain to access the college portal, MyBC. Use of the college portal is optional for student users however we are unable to provide access to the services and resources provided only within the portal such as access to some class materials (delivered through MyBC Class Sites), access to college forums, blogs, personal sites or other collaborative portal features.

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

### Campus Emergency Alerts System (Subscription)

Bellevue College may require you to provide certain personal information in order to subscribe to receive text message alerts or e-mail alerts whenever there is a campus emergency or unplanned closure.  The information is required in order to verify your identity. If you choose not to provide this information via the web we will be unable to send alerts to you during campus emergency situations. Emergency information will still be available to you, but you will need to visit the Bellevue College website or call (425) 401-6680 to get information about a college emergency or unplanned closure. 

Note: Existing laws and regulations may prevent Bellevue College from disclosing personal information about you. Get details about regulations that protect disclosure of your personal information.

## Review and Correction of Personally Identifiable Information

You can review any personally identifiable information we collect about you by using the information in the Contact Information section at the end of this Notice.  You may recommend changes to your personally identifiable information you believe to be inaccurate by submitting in writing or via e-mail a  request that credibly shows the inaccuracy.  We will take reasonable steps to verify your identity before granting access or making corrections.  ([RCW 43.105.310](http://apps.leg.wa.gov/RCW/default.aspx?cite=43.105.310)) 

## Cookies

Bellevue College uses "cookies" to personalize (customize) your experience when browsing the college website. Cookies are simple text files stored on your computer by your web browser.  Cookies that are created when browsing our website do not contain personal identifiable information about you and do not compromise your privacy or security. The cookie feature used on the Bellevue College website stores a randomly generated identifying tag on your computer.

The Bellevue College “Get Started” site utilizes cookies to automatically identify you, allowing you to determine if you want the site to remember your username and password when you visit the site. Cookies used on this site are encrypted and do not save your personal information. If you have chosen to disable cookies in your browser, you will still have access to the services offered on this site however you will not have access to the auto log-in feature. 

## Security

Bellevue College, as developer and manager of the BC website, has taken several steps to safeguard the integrity of its data and prevent unauthorized access to information maintained by Bellevue College.  These measures are designed and intended to prevent corruption of data, block unknown or unauthorized access to our systems and information, and to provide reasonable protection of private information in our possession. 

This information should not be construed in any way as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as fail proof the security of information provided via Bellevue College’s websites.

## Disclaimer

The BC website contains many links to other websites.  These include links to websites operated by other government agencies, nonprofit organizations and private businesses.  When you follow links to other sites and leave our website, information contained in this Privacy Notice no longer applies.  When you transfer to another website, you are subject to the privacy policy of that new site.

Reference in this website to any specific commercial products, processes, or services, or the use of any trade, firm, or corporation name is for the information and convenience of the public, and does not constitute endorsement, recommendation, or favoring by the State of Washington, Bellevue College, or its officers, employees or agents.

Neither the State of Washington, nor any agency, officer, or employee of the State of Washington warrants the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of any information published by this system, nor endorses any content, viewpoints, products, or services linked from this system, and shall not be held liable for any losses caused by reliance on the accuracy, reliability or timeliness of such information. Portions of such information may be incorrect or not current. Any person or entity that relies on any information obtained from this system does so at its own risk.  Under no circumstances shall BC be liable for damages arising out of or in connection with the use of or inability to use this site.   This is a comprehensive limitation of liability that applies to all damages of any kind, include without limitation compensatory, direct, indirect or consequential damages, loss of date, income or profit, loss of or damage to property and claims of third parties.

Bellevue College reserves the right to in its discretion, to change or modify all or any part of these terms and conditions at any time, effective immediately upon notice published on this web site.   

To review your personal information, or request correction of your personal information, you may contact Bellevue College as follows:

Matt Groshong, Interim Registrar   
Student Services, Room B125Q   
Bellevue College   
3000 Landerholm Circle SE   
Bellevue, WA 98007   
Fax: (425) 564-6181   
Phone: (425) 564-5608   
E-mail: [matt.groshong@bellevuecollege.edu](mailto:matt.groshong@bellevuecollege.edu)

To offer comments about Bellevue College’s website or about the information presented in this Privacy Notice:

Information Resources  
Mailstop N215  
Bellevue College  
3000 Landerholm Circle SE  
Bellevue WA, 98007  
Phone: (425) 564-2459  
E-mail: [webmaster@bellevuecollege.edu](mailto:webmaster@bellevuecollege.edu)
